I'm gonna turn over the next card. Concentrate.
我要揭下一張牌了，集中精神
What do you think it is?
你認為這是什么？
- A square. - Good guess, but wrong.
-正方形 -猜得好，但錯了
Clear your head.
想清楚
- What do you think it is? - Is it a star?.
-你認為這是什么？ -是星星嗎？
It is a star. Very good.
這確實是星星，真棒
Think hard. What is it?
用心想想，是什么？
- A circle. - Close, but definitely wrong.
-圓圈 -接近了，但仍不對
All right. Ready?.
好了，準備就緒了嗎？
What is it?
是什么？
Figure eight.
數字八
Incredible. Can you see these?
真厲害，你能看穿東西嗎？
- Are you cheating? - No, they're just coming to me.
-你在騙我嗎？ -不，是直覺
- Nervous? - Yes. I don't like this.
-緊張嗎？ -對，我不喜歡這樣
You only have 75 more to go. What's this one?
你只剩75，這張是什么？
- A couple of wavy lines. - This isn't your lucky day.
-一些波紋 -你真倒霉
- I'm getting tired of this! - You volunteered.
-我對這游戲感到厭倦 -是你自愿的
I didn't know about the chocks. What are you trying to prove?
但不知要被電擊，你想怎樣？
I'm studying the effect of negative reinforcement on ESP.
我在研究超感覺的負強化效果
The effect is that it's pissing me off!
效果是令我光火
- Then maybe my theory is correct! - Kéep the five bucks!
-也許我的理論是正確的 -那些錢留給你吧
Get used to that.
你得逐漸適應
That's the kind of resentment your ability will provoke in people.
因你的能力會引起別人的憤怒
- Do you think I have it? - You're no fluke, Jennifer.
-你認為我有嗎？ -這不是僥幸，珍妮佛
This is it!
就是它！
I need the UV lenses and the tape for the video camera.
我要紫外線鏡和空白錄影帶
Will you excuse me?
恕我失陪
I'm in the middle of something, Ray.
雷伊，我正漸入佳境
Could you come back in an hour?.
你一小時后回來好嗎？
Peter, at 1 :40 PM, at the New York Public Library, -
彼得，下午一點四十分 在紐約圖書館
- ten people saw a free-floating, vaporous apparition.
有十個人見到幽靈出現
It blew books off shelves from 20 feet away!
書架上的書本被吹到二十英尺外
I'm very excited.
我很興奮
Check it out and get back to me.
那你檢查后向我報告
You're coming with us. Spengler took PKE valences that buried the needle.
跟我同去，斯彭勒帶了原子價
We're close on this one. I can feel it.
我感到我們很接近它 我可以感覺到
We're very, very close.
我們非常接近了
I have to go now. Could you come back, say at ...
我要走了，你能在…
- Eight o'clock?. - That's what I was going to say.
-八點鐘回來嗎？ -真是心有靈犀
You've finally gone around the bend.
最后輪到你瘋了
You've been meeting every schizo who's had a paranormal experience.
你遇到的那些人 只是受超自然經歷困擾
I was present at an unexplained mass sponge migration.
但我看過大量海綿無故移民
The sponges migrated a foot and a half.
它們走了一英尺半
You're here! This is very big, Peter.
你到了，彼得，這個很大呢
Remember the time you tried to drill a hole through your head?
還記得你想在頭上鉆個洞嗎？
- I'm Roger Delacorte. - I'm Dr. Venkman, Dr. Stanz, Egon.
-我是羅杰德拉科 -文卡曼、斯坦和埃貢
Thank you for coming. I hope we can clear this up quietly.
謝謝你來了， 希望可悄悄趕走它們
Let's not rush things. We don't know what we have.
別著急，我們還不知道是什么
- It had arms. It reached for me. - Arms! I can't wait to see it!
-有手臂碰到我 -手臂，我想大開眼界呢
Let me ask you a couple of standard questions.
讓我問你一些例行問題
Have you or anyone in your family ever been diagnosed schizophrenic?
你家有人患有精神分裂癥嗎？
- My uncle thought he was a saint. - I'd call that a big "yes".
-我叔叔總以圣人自居 -很好呢
- Do you use drugs or alcohol? - No!
-你曾吸過毒或酗過酒嗎？ -沒有
Just asking. Are you menstruating right now?.
順便問一問，你正來月經嗎？
- What has that got to do with it? - Back off. I'm a scientist.
-有什么關系？ -且慢，我是科學家
Ray! It's moving!
雷伊，它移動了
Look.
看
This is hot.
這里很接近
Symmetrical book stacking, just like in Philadelphia, 1947.
對稱書堆，像1947年的費城
You're right. No human being would stack books like this.
對，人類倒不會這樣做
Listen! Do you smell something?
注意！你聞到什么了嗎？
Talk about telekinetic activity. Look at this mess!
關于通靈活動，看這里一團糟
- Look at this. - Ectoplasmic residue.
-看 -是流質殘余物
- Get a sample of this. - It's the real thing.
-拿個樣本 -這是真的
Someone blows their nose and you want to keep it?
有鼻涕，你要嗎？
- There's more over here. - I'm getting stronger readings.
-這邊還有更多 -反應強烈
This way!
這邊
Egon, your mucous.
埃貢，你的粘液
Has this happened to you before?
你以前見過這情況嗎？
First time?
是第一次嗎？
It's here.
在這里
A full-torso apparition, and it's real.
是軀干幽靈，是真的
So what do we do?
那我們該怎么辦？
Could you come over and talk to me for a second? Right over here.
你可否到這里來談談？ 到這里來
- What do we do? - What do you think?.
-我們怎么辦？ -你認為呢？
Stop that!
停下
- One of us should speak to it. - Good idea.
-我們中該有一人去告訴她 -好提議
Hello, I'm Peter.
你好，我是彼得
Where are you from ... originally?.
你原本…來自哪里？
- The usual stuff isn't working. - I know exactly what to do.
-用普通方法不行 -我知道怎么做
Stay close.
走近她
Do exactly as I say. Get ready.
照我說的去做，準備
Ready?. Get her!
準備好了沒有？抓住她
- Did you see it? What was it? - We'll get back to you.
-你看到了嗎？是什么？ -我們會回來幫你
"Get her!" That was your whole plan.
“抓住她！” 這是你的全部計劃
- It was scientific. - I just got over-excited.
-很有科學性 -我只是過度興奮
But we touched the etheric plane. Do you know what this means?
但這東西虛無飄渺，明白嗎？
I'm very excited.
我很興奮
We have an excellent chance of catching a ghost and holding it.
我們大有機會抓到魔鬼
This is great! lf the ionisation rate is constant, -
真棒，如果電離率是固定的話
- we could really bust some heads!
我們可以砍掉他的頭顱
- Are you serious about this? - I'm always serious.
-你是認真的嗎？ -我經常這樣的
I'm going to take back what I said about you.
我會收回剛才談到你的話
You've earned it.
你應得的
The possibilities are limitless. Hey, Dean Yeager!
可能是沒有限制，耶格爾院長
- Are you giving us better quarters? - You're being moved offcampus.
-我們會搬進更好的宿舍嗎？ -你被趕出校園了
Your grant has been terminated and you are to leave immediately.
你的基金已中止，要馬上離開
This is preposterous. I demand an explanation.
真荒謬，我要求解釋
The university will no longer fund your activities.
大學不會再資助你們的活動
- But the kids love us. - Dr. Venkman ...
-但我們受到學生愛戴 -文卡曼博士…
The purpose of science is to serve mankind, -
科學是替人類服務的
- but you regard it as a kind of dodge or hustle.
但你卻視為一種逃避或浪費
Your theories are popular tripe and your conclusions are questionable.
你廢話連篇，結論可疑
- You are a poor scientist. - I see.
-你是個可憐的科學家 -我明白了
You have no place in this university.
你在這個大學沒有地位了
What a disgrace. MIT or Stanford wouldn't touch us now.
真丟臉，麻省理工或史丹佛 現在不會找我們了
- Einstein worked as a patent clerk. - Do you know how much they earn?
-愛因斯坦曾當特許狀文員 -你知道他們賺多少錢嗎？
The university gave us money. We didn't have to produce anything.
我們不用生產，大學也會付薪
You've never been out of college. The private sector expects results.
你從來沒有出過大學 但私人機構注重成果呢
For whatever reasons, Ray ... Call it fate ...
什么原因也好…是天意…
... call it luck, call it karma ...
是運氣或是因果…
... I believe everything happens for a reason.
我相信凡事總有原因
- We were destined to be thrown out. - Why?.
-我們注定被拒絕 -為什么？
To go into business for ourselves.
那我們自己創業吧
This containment system will cost a load of bread.
那牽制系統價值不菲
Where will we get the money?.
我們哪里有錢？
I don't know.
我不知道
- You won't regret this, Ray. - I was born in that house.
-你不會后悔的 -我在這房子出生的
- Everyone has three mortgages. - At 19%? You didn't even bargain.
-所有人都抵押過三次 -19%？但你不會討價還價
The interest rate alone for the first five years comes to $95,000.
頭五年的利息有九萬五
We are establishing the defence science of the next decade.
我們制定未來十年的防御科學
"Professional paranormal investigations and Eliminations."
專業的超感覺研究和清除
The franchise rights alone will make us rich.
擁有專利權就發達了
There's office space, sleeping quarters and a full kitchen.
那里有辦公室、睡房和廚房
It seems a little pricey for a fixer-upper.
對北部人來說是奢侈品
- What do you think, Egon? - This building should be condemned.
-埃貢，你認為呢？ -這建筑物真該死
There's metal fatigue, the wiring is inadequate for our power needs, -
這里有金屬疲勞，電力不足
- and the neighbourhood is like a demilitarised zone.
附近就像裁軍區
Hey! Does this pole still work?.
這柱子仍有用嗎？
This place is great! When can we move in? You have to try this pole.
這地方真不錯， 何時搬進來？你應試試這柱子
I'll get my stuff.
我去把東西拿來
We should stay here tonight. Sleep here. To try it out.
我們今晚該睡在這里，試一試
- We'll take it. - Good.
-那成交了 -好
Hi.
你好
Dana, it's you. I thought it was the drugstore.
丹娜，是你呀， 我以為是藥店職員
- Are you sick?. - No. I just ordered more vitamins.
-你病了嗎？ -不，我訂了維他命丸
I played "20-Minute Workout" at high speed and got a 10-minute workout.
我共進行三十分鐘快速訓練
- Would you like a mineral water?. - I have to go to rehearsal now.
-你要礦泉水嗎？ -我現在要去彩排
I'll take a rain check. I always have mineral water in the house.
改天吧，我屋里常常有礦泉水
I'm having a big party. My fourth anniversary as an accountant.
我要開個大派對 慶祝當四年會計師
- I'd like you to stop by. - I'll try to stop by, Louis.
-我想你出席 -我也想，路易斯
You left your TV on. The creep down the hall phoned the manager.
有住客投訴你的電視機聲很大
I didn't know I left it on.
我不知道電視機開著呢
I tried to disconnect the cable, but I couldn't get in, -
我想關掉它，但無法進去
- so I turned up my TV, too, so everyone would think ...
我也開著電視機，讓所有人以為…
I'll see you later!
待會見
I'm gonna have a shower!
我要去洗澡
- Do you hearnoises atnight? - Do you dreadyour attic?
-你晚上有聽到怪聲嗎？ -你害怕住頂樓嗎？
- Have you everseen a ghost? - Ifso, don't walt anotherminute.
-你見過魔鬼嗎？ -如果是真的，那火速行動吧
Call Ghostbusters.
打電話給魔鬼克星吧
Our staffis on call 24 hours a day to serve your needs.
我們二十四小時恭候
We're ready to believe you.
只有我們才相信你
Is it too subtle? Do you think people may not see the sign?
這個太小了， 別人會看到這標志嗎？
You can't park that here!
你不能停在這里
I found a car. It needs some suspension work, -
我找到車子，它需要一些懸架
- shocks, brakes, brake pads, lining, steering box ...
防震器、剎車墊和方向裝置…
- How much? - Only 4,800. Rings, mufflers ...
-多少錢？ -四千八，圓環、消音器…
- Janine, any calls or messages? - No.
-珍妮，有電話或者留言嗎？ -沒有
- Any customers? - No, Dr. Venkman.
-有顧客嗎？ -沒有，文卡曼博士
Good job, isn't it? Type something, we're paying you.
這工作不錯吧？ 那打字吧，我們會付錢給你的
Don't stare. You've got those bug eyes.
別盯著我，你的眼睛很嚇人
Janine! Sorry about the "bug eyes" thing. I'll be in my office.
珍妮，對不起說你瞪眼睛， 我在辦公室
You're very handy. I can tell.
我知道你是好幫手
- I bet you like to read, too. - Print is dead.
-你也喜歡閱讀 -印刷是死的
I read a lot myself. Some people think I'm too intellectual, -
我常看書，有人當我知識分子
- but it's a great way to spend your spare time. I also play racquetball.
但要善用余暇，我也會打網球
- Do you have any hobbies? - I collect spores and fungus.
-你有什么嗜好？ -我收集芽胞和真菌
Hello.
有人嗎？
- Is this the Ghostbusters office? - Yes. Can I help you?
-是魔鬼克星的辦公室嗎？ -對，有什么可幫你的？
I don't have an appointment. I'd like to talk to someone, please.
我沒有預約，我想跟負責人談
- I'm Peter Venkman. May I help you? - I don't know ...
-我是彼得，有什么可幫忙？ -我不知道…
- It may sound unusual. - That's all we get around here.
-聽起來很荒謬 -我們正是處理這類事的
- Come into my office, Miss ... - Barrett. Dana Barrett.
-到我辦公室，小姐… -丹娜巴雷特
And the voice said "Zuul". I slammed the refrigerator door and left.
有聲音說祖伊， 我關了冰箱的門就離開了
Odd behaviour for a major appliance. What do you think it was?
你怎看到電器有怪異行為？
If I knew, I wouldn't be here.
我要知道就不會來這里了
- Egon, what do you think?. - She's telling the truth.
-埃貢，你認為呢？ -她沒有撒謊
Of course I am. Who would make up a story like that?
當然，誰會虛構那樣的故事？
Nutballs who come in off the street.
街上的瘋子
It could be past life experience intruding on present time.
也有可能受到過去的經歷影響
I wouldn't rule out clairvoyance or telepathic contact, either.
我不排除是神視或通靈接觸
- I don't believe in any of it. - That's all right. I don't either.
-我不相信 -算了吧，我也不信
But there are some procedures which often bring us results.
但不能忽視引起 這種現象的過程
I'll check the building's records for a history of psychic turbulence.
我去查查大廈出現鬼怪的記錄
I'll look for the name "Zuul" in Tobin's Spirit Guide.
我要查看靈界手冊，找出祖伊
I'll take Miss Barrett home and check herout.
我會帶小姐回家檢查
I'll go check out her apartment. Okay?.
檢查她的寓所，行嗎？
If something is going to happen, I want it to happen to me first.
如有事發生，我想第一個知道
That's the closet.
那是衣櫥
They hate this. I like to torture them.
他們討厭這個，我要折磨他們
That's right, boys. It's Dr. Venkman!
好了，我是文卡曼博士
A lot of space.
地方挺大呢
- Just you? - Yes.
-你一個人住嗎？ -對
Good.
好
- What are you doing? - It's technical.
-你在做什么？ -這是儀器
One of our little toys.
其中一件小玩意
That's the bedroom. But nothing ever happened in there.
那是睡房，但沒事發生過
What a crime ...
是罪案的溫床…
- You don't act like a scientist. - They're usually pretty stiff.
-你倒不像科學家 -它們很倔強的
You're more like a game-show host.
你好像在主持游戲節目
That's the kitchen?
那是廚房嗎？
- Are these the eggs? - Yes.
-是這些蛋嗎？ -對
Theyjumped out of their shells and cooked on the counter.
蛋黃脫殼而出，在桌面上變熟
And that's when I heard that noise coming from the refrigerator.
然后冰箱傳出聲音
Would you like to check the refrigerator?.
你去看看冰箱好嗎？
Let me check the fridge. Good call.
讓我看看吧，說得好
Oh, my God. Look at all the junk food!
天啊，全是垃圾食物
This wasn't here. There was nothing here. There was a space, -
不是這樣的，沒有東西在這里 那是一個空間
- and a building with flames coming out of it. And there were creatures.
有建筑物冒煙，還有怪物
They were growling and snarling, and I heard a voice say "Zuul".
它們大叫什么“祖伊”
- I'm not getting any reading. - Are you using that correctly?.
-但儀器沒有反應 -你會用嗎？
I think so. There are no animals in there.
當然，里面根本沒有動物
Either I have a monster in my kitchen or I'm crazy.
不是有怪物就是我瘋了
- I don't think you're crazy. - That makes me feel so much better.
-你沒有瘋 -你這樣說我就放心了
All I have is my work. There's nothing else in my life.
工作就是我的生命
I meet you, and I say, "There's someone with the same problem."
我告訴你，我碰到了你
We both have the same problem: You.
我們的相同問題就是：你
I'm gonna go for broke.
我快破產了
- I am madly in love with you. - Will you please leave?
-我深深地愛上你 -請你離開好嗎？
Then she threw me out of her life. She thought I was a creep.
她拒絕我，因她以為我是怪物
You are so odd.
你真是莫明其妙
- No ... - I've got it!
-不… -我明白了
- I'll prove myself to you. - That's not necessary.
-我會證明給你看 -不用了
I'll solve your problem. Then you'll say:
我能幫你解決問題，而你說
"Venkman gets things done."
文卡曼成功了
"l wonder what makes him tick. Would he like to know what makes me tick?. "
他為什么能行？我怎樣才行？
- You'll think of me after I'm gone. - I bet I will.
-我走后，你會懷念我 -我會的
No kiss?
不吻別嗎？
- To our first customer. - To our first and only customer.
-為我們首個顧客干杯 -為我們第一和唯一的顧客干杯
I need some cash. I should take her out to dinner.
我要些錢， 我應該約她出去吃飯
This feast represents the last of the petty cash.
這一餐代表我們的錢所剩不多
Slow down.
慢慢來
Hello, Ghostbusters. Of course they're serious.
魔鬼克星，他們很認真的
You do? You have?
你有嗎？
No kidding?
不是在說笑嗎？
Just give me the address.
把地址給我
Of course, they'll be totally discreet.
好的，他們行事絕對保密
Thank you. We got one!
謝謝，有生意了
It's a call!
有客人打電話來
Hey, has anybody seen a ghost?
有人見到魔鬼嗎？
Thank you for coming so quickly. They're starting to ask questions.
謝謝你們來得真快， 他們開始發問了
- Has it happened before? - We all know about the 12th floor.
-有前科嗎？ -只知道在十二樓
It's been quiet for years, until two weeks ago. It was never this bad.
多年來一直很平靜， 兩周前才出現，從未見過
- Did you ever report it? - Heavens, no.
-有報警嗎？ -天，沒有
The owners don't like us to talk about it. Can we handle it quietly?.
業主不想公開，希望悄悄處理
Don't worry. We handle this kind of thing all the time.
放心，我們經常處理這些事
Are you supposed to be a cosmonaut?
你是太空人嗎？
We're exterminators. Someone saw a cockroach on twelve.
是滅蟲員，十二樓發現蟑螂
- That's got to be some cockroach. - It'll bite your head off.
-一定是有蟑螂 -會咬掉你的頭顱
- Going up? - I'll take the next one.
-上去嗎？ -我搭下一部
We really haven't had a successful test of this equipment.
我們尚未成功測試這儀器
- I blame myself. - No sense worrying now.
-都是我不好 -別擔心
Why worry?. Each of us is wearing an unlicensed nuclear accelerator.
為什么不擔心？ 我們配備無牌核子加速器
Let's get ready. Switch me on.
準備就緒，把我的打開
What the hell are you doing?
你們在搞什么鬼？
- Sorry. - We thought you were someone else.
-抱歉 -我們認錯人了
- Successful test. - I guess so.
-測試成功 -對
- We better split up. - We can do more damage that way.
-我們分頭行事 -這樣可以造成更大的破壞
Venkman!
文卡曼
Disgusting blob ... I'll have to hold him myself.
討厭鬼…我要親自抓住他
- Come in, Ray. - Venkman! I saw it! I saw it!
-雷伊，答話 -文卡曼，我看到了
- It's right here, looking at me. - He's an ugly little spud.
-在這里，它在看著我 -它很丑陋
- I think he can hear you. - Don't move. It won't hurt you.
-我認為它會聽到你的 -別動，不會傷害你的
- What happened? - He slimed me.
-什么事？ -它向我吐粘液
Great! Actual physical contact. Can you move?
太棒了，這是身體接觸， 你能動嗎？
- Ray! Come in, please. - Spengler, I'm with Venkman!
-雷伊，答話 -斯彭勒，我跟文卡曼在一起
- He got slimed! - Great. Save some forme.
-它渾身都是粘液 -留一些給我
Get down here. It wentinto a ballroom.
下樓，它去了大舞廳
If you and your staff could wait here, we'll take care of everything.
全都留在這里，我們會處理的
There it is! On the ceiling!
那里有，在天花板上面
That's the one that got me.
剛才就是它抓著我
Ready?. Throw it!
準備，射
- I did that. It's my fault. - The table broke the fall.
-是我做的，我錯了 -桌子擋住了它
I forgot to tell you not to cross the streams.
我忘了說，光線不能相交
- Why?. - It would be bad.
-為什么？ -這樣就糟了
What do you mean, bad?
糟了，什么意思？
Imagine all life stopping and every molecule in your body exploding.
如生命停止， 身體內的分子爆炸
- Total protonic reversal. - That's bad. Important safety tip.
-是質子逆轉 -對，是重要安全提示
Ray, take the left. Egon, take the right.
雷伊左邊，埃貢右邊
Ray, give me one high and outside.
雷伊，包圍它
All right. Hold it! Nice shooting, Tex!
拿穩，射得好
The room will be ready as soon as your guests are with us.
你的嘉賓到齊后就可以進去了
He's gonna move! I need some room to put the trap down!
它要移動了， 我需要地方放下捕捉機
Excuse me, please.
失陪
- We have to get this in the clear. - Wait! I always wanted to do this.
-我們要移走這個 -等一下，我想做這工作
- The flowers are still standing. - I want a confinement stream. Go!
-花兒還屹立不倒 -我要限制光線
Hold him up there! He's gonna move! Go!
繼續，別讓它溜走
- It's working, Ray. - Start bringing him down.
-成功了 -把它帶下來
Maybe now you won't slime a guy with one of these.
也許你不會向人吐這些東西
Shorten your stream!
縮短光線
- Don't look directly in the trap. - I looked in the trap, Ray.
-別看著捕捉機 -我正看著它，雷伊
Bring your streams off when I close the trap. Now!
我關上捕捉機后停止發射
It's in there.
它在里面
That wasn't such a chore.
這工作輕而易舉呢
- I want that door open now. - Stand over there.
-我想現在開門 -站在那邊
- We came, saw and kicked its ass! - Did you see it?
-我們大功告成了 -你看到了嗎？
- What is it? Will there be more? - A focused, non-terminal phantasm.
-是什么？還有嗎？ -是聚焦的不死鬼
A class-5, full-roaming vapour. A nasty one, too.
五級氣體，也很難聞
Let's talk seriously.
讓我們認真地談談
The entrapment will cost $4,000, -
那捕捉機要四千元
- but we have a special on storage of the beast for $1 ,000.
儲存怪物要一千元
$5,000? I won't pay it.
五千元？我不付
That's all right, we can just put it back.
那算了，我們把它放出來
No, no! All right. Anything.
不，你要什么都行
Thank you. Hope we can help you again.
謝謝，希望再次光顧
Today, the entire Eastern Seaboard is talking ofparanormal activity.
超自然活動成為東岸話題
Alleged ghostsightings have been reported across the tri-state area.
據報三個州都出現了鬼怪
My Grandma would spin yarns about a spectral locomotive -
從前奶奶說有幽靈火車頭
- that would rocket past her farm, but now ...
從她的農場開過，但現在…
Ghost Fever Grips New York
“紐約掀起了抓魔鬼熱潮”
Ghost Cops Bust Chinatown Spook
“魔鬼克星直闖唐人街”
The phone-in topic is ghostbusting. More sightings are reported.
是魔鬼克星，不少人說見過鬼
Some maintain that the paranormal eliminators are the cause of it all.
有人指這是魔鬼克星所為
The Ghostbusters are atlt again. This time, at a fashionable club.
魔鬼克星這次在 高級的俱樂部出現
They fought the pesky poltergeist, then danced the night away-
他們與吵鬧鬼打架，然后跟…
- wlth some ofthe ladies who wltnessed the disturbance.
目擊事件的女士起舞
24 hours a day, 7 days a week. No job's too big. No fee's too big.
每天24小時，每周七天， 隨時候命，收費便宜
Does it have arms and legs?
它有手臂和腳嗎？
There's one big question on everybody's mind:
每個人腦里都有一個重要問題
"How is Elvis?"
就是“貓王好嗎？”
Do you believe in UFOs, astral projections, telepathy, ESP, -
你相信天外來客，幽浮、 靈魂和通靈…
- full-trance mediums, the Loch Ness monster and the theory of Atlantis?
招魂、怪物和阿特蘭大理論？
If there's a steady paycheque, I'll believe anything.
如有薪水支付， 我會相信任何事
- I have to get some sleep. - You don't look good.
-我要睡一覺 -你臉色很差
- I don't? - You didn't use to look like this.
-是嗎？ -你以前不是這樣的
- Here's the paper on Brooklyn. - Here's tonight's worksheet.
-這是布魯克林報紙 -今晚的工作表
- Mr. Zeddmore came about the job. - You're hired. Ray Stanz, Venkman.
-齊德莫先生來找工作 -你獲聘了，雷伊，文卡曼
Can you help me, please?
請你幫我拿著好嗎？
Welcome aboard.
歡迎加入
These guest conductors shouldn't scream at us in German.
那客席指揮家 不該用德語對我們尖叫
The man isn't competent to conduct a symphony orchestra.
他根本不懂指揮交響樂團
Could you wait here a minute?
你在這里稍等好嗎？
- This is a surprise. - That was a wonderful rehearsal.
-這真是個驚喜 -彩排很出色
- You're the best one in your row. - Most people can't single me out.
-你的表演最棒了 -很多人分辨不出我
I don't have to take this abuse from you. Everyone wants to abuse me.
我不想你罵我，很多人想罵我
You're a big celebrity now. Do you have some information for me?
你現在很有名， 有消息告訴我嗎？
- Who's the stiff? - One of the world's best musicians.
-那家伙是誰？ -世界一流音樂家之一
- Do you have information for me? - I'd rather tell you in private.
-有我案件的資料嗎？ -我想私下跟你談
I found the name "Zuul".
我找到“祖伊”這名字
It refers to a demigod worshipped around 6000 BC by the ...
是公元前六千年的 一個半神半人
- Hittites. - The Mesopotamians and Sumerians.
-受到赫梯人崇拜 -美索不達米亞人和蘇美爾人
Zuul was the minion of Gozer. What's Gozer?.
祖伊是戈薩寵兒，戈薩是誰？
- Gozer was very big in Sumeria. - What's he doing in my icebox?.
-戈薩在蘇美爾很有名 -他在我冰箱里做什么？
Could we meet Thursday night and exchange information?
我們可在星期四晚上 見面并交換資料嗎？
I can't. I'm busy.
不行，我很忙
You seem to think there is something wrong up here.
你定是以為我腦袋有問題
That I enjoy spending my evenings with my clients. No ...
以為我愛跟客人 共度晚上的時光，不…
I'm making an exception in your case because ...
但跟你就例外，因為…
... I respect you. As an artist, and as a dresser, too.
我尊重你是個藝術家和服裝師
This is magnificent.
過獎了
- I'll see you Thursday. - I'll bring the Roylance Guide.
-星期四見 -我會把手冊帶來
- Who the hell is that? - Just an old friend.
-那人是誰？ -只是舊朋友
See you Thursday! Sorry I didn't get to meet you, sir.
星期四見，但不是你，先生
I'm glad you feeling better. You're still pale, though.
很高興你好些了， 但臉色仍很蒼白
- What does he do? - He's a scientist.
-他做什么？ -他是科學家
This is where we store all the vapours and slimers we trap.
這是儲存蒸汽和粘液的地方
A loaded trap here. Open. Unlock the system. Insert the trap.
捕捉機滿了，打開系統放進去
Release.
放手
Close. Lock the system. Set your entry grid.
關閉后再調校系統
Neutronise the field. When the light is green, the trap is clean.
中性區域，綠燈亮起 表示已清理了捕捉機
The ghost is incarcerated.
魔鬼被殲滅了
- There's a man from the EPA here. - What does he want?
-有環保部門人員來了 -他想怎樣？
I don't know. I'm working too hard. You promised to hire more help.
不知道，我正忙得很 但你答應請人幫我的
Someone with your qualifications could easily find a good job -
若他們有你的學歷， 也許會找到好工作
- in either food service or housekeeping.
會做食物店工作或管理家務
- Are you gonna answer that? - I've quit betterjobs than this.
-你要接聽嗎？ -我竟辭了一份優差
- Ghostbusters! What do you want? - Can I help you?
-魔鬼克星，什么事？ -有什么可以幫忙的？
I'm Walter Peck. I represent the Environmental Protection Agency.
我是帕克，環境保護局職員
Great. How's it going down there?
有何貴干？
- Are you Peter Venkman? - Yes, I'm Dr. Venkman.
-你是彼得文卡曼嗎？ -對，文卡曼博士
- Exactly what are you a doctor of? - Parapsychology and psychology.
-確切的說你是什么博士？ -通靈學和心理學
I see. And now you catch ghosts.
而現在從事抓魔鬼工作
You could say that.
你可以這樣說的
- How many have you caught? - I'm not at liberty to say.
-你抓到了多少？ -我不能隨便說
Where do you put these ghosts once you catch them?
你抓到它后， 把魔鬼放在哪里？
Into a storage facility.
儲存庫內
- Is the facility on these premises? - Yes.
-那儀器在這里嗎？ -在
- May I see the storage facility?. - No.
-我可以看看嗎？ -不行
- Why not? - You did not use the magic word.
-為什么？ -你沒有說咒語
- What is the magic word? - "Please".
-什么咒語？ -“請”
- May I please see the facility?. - Why do you want to see it?
-請問我可否看看儀器？ -為什么要看？
I want to know what you do here. There are wild stories in the media.
了解你工作，外面有很多流言
We want to assess any environmental impact from your operation, -
我們想評估 你的行動對環境的影響
- Iike the presence of noxious, hazardous chemicals.
好像有什么有害的化學物質
You show me, or I'll get a court order.
你讓我看，或是我申請法院指示
I'll sue your ass for wrongful prosecution.
我就會告你毀謗
You can have it your way.
隨便你吧
It's crowded in there, and my data points to something big.
有數據顯示有大事發生
What do you mean, big?
大事，什么意思？
Say this Twinkie depicts the normal amount of psychokinetic energy ...
這小點心代表心靈移動的能量
According to this morning's sample, it would be a Twinkie 35 feet long.
早上的樣本是35英尺長
That's a big Twinkie.
那是巨型小點心
We could be on the verge of a PKE surge of dangerous proportions.
我們可能正處于危險邊緣
We just had a visit from the Environmental Protection Agency.
有環境保護局人員到訪
- Tell him about the Twinkie. - What about the Twinkie?
-把小點心的事告訴他 -什么小點心？
Dana, it's you! Come in. You're missing a classic party.
丹娜，進來， 你錯過了很棒的派對呢
I have a date.
但我有約會
You made a date? Tonight?
你有了約會？今晚嗎？
I'm sorry, Louis. I forgot.
抱歉，路易斯，我忘了
That's okay, you can bring him along.
沒問題，你可帶他一起來
Maybe we'll stop by, okay?.
也許逗留一會兒吧
I'll tell everybody you're coming. We're gonna play Twister and ...
那我告訴他們，我們會玩游戲
Let me in! It's Louis!
讓我進去，我是路易斯
Hello ... Hi, Mom. I've been busy.
喂…你好，媽媽，我挺忙的
Oh, I am ... I will.
我會了
I won't. Mom, I have to go. I have a date.
不會的，我要去赴約
No one you know.
你不認識的
He's a Ghostbuster.
是魔鬼克星成員
I'll have to let you know. Love to Dad. Bye.
我會告訴你的，向爸爸問好
Oh, shit.
糟了
- Do you have any Exedrin? - I have acetylsalicylic acid.
-你有埃瑟林嗎？ -我有阿斯匹靈
Smoked salmon from Nova Scotia, $24.95 a pound.
加拿大熏三文魚， 每磅24.95元
It only cost $14.12 after taxes.
扣稅后只售14.12元
- Louis, I'm going home. - Don't leave yet.
-路易斯，我回家了 -別走
Maybe if we start dancing, others will join in.
也許我們跳舞，其他人會加入
Okay.
好的
I've got to get the door.
我去應門
Ted! Annette! I'm glad you came!
泰德、安妮特，你們來了真好
This is Ted and Annette Flemming!
這是泰德和安妮特
Ted has a business in receivership.
泰德有一間小型的地毯店
Annette's drawing a salary from a deferred bonus.
安妮特兩年前開始收延期紅利
They have 15,000 left on the house. So they're okay!
其房子有一萬五千元，沒問題
Who wants to play Parcheesi?
誰想玩巴棋戲？
Help! There's a bear loose in my apartment!
救命，我家里發現了熊
A bear in his apartment ...
他家里有熊…
There are not supposed to be pets in the building.
這座樓不該有寵物的
Let me in. There's got to be a way in here.
讓我進去，一定有辦法進去的
Let me in!
讓我進去
Nice doggie. Maybe I have a Milkbone.
乖，也許我有牛乳骨頭
- What happened? - Someone brought a cougar in here.
-什么事？ -有人帶來了美洲獅
I'm going to Dana Barrett's.
我到丹娜巴雷特那里去
Hello.
你好
- That's a different look for you. - Are you the Kéymaster?.
-你的樣子不同了 -你是主人嗎？
Not that I know of.
不是我認識的人
- Are you the Kéymaster. - Yes. I'm a friend of his.
-對，我是他的朋友
- I didn't get your name. - I am Zuul, the Gatekeeper.
-我不知道你的名字 -守門員祖伊
- What are we doing today?. - Preparing for the coming of Gozer.
-我們做什么？ -準備迎接戈薩
The Destructor.
破壞者
Are we still going out?
我們還要出去嗎？
You could have picked up the place.
你可以收拾一下地方
- Do you want this body?. - Is this a trick question?
-你要這身體嗎？ -有弦外之音嗎？
- I guess the roses worked. - Take me now, sub-creature.
-我猜是玫瑰的功效 -次生物，來吧
We never talk anymore.
我們不再談話了
I make it a rule not to get involved with possessed people.
我不準自己跟瘋子扯上關系
- It's really more of a guideline. - I want you inside me.
-不只是守則 -我想你進入我的身體
I can't. You have at least two people in there already.
不行，你體內有兩個人了
It might be a little crowded. Stop disturbing Dr. Venkman and relax.
也許有些擠， 別騷擾文卡曼，別緊張
Put your hands on your chest.
把雙手放在胸前
What I'd really like to do is talk to Dana.
我想跟丹娜談談
- Dana, it's Peter. - There is no Dana, only Zuul.
-丹娜，是彼得 -這里沒有丹娜，只有祖伊
Zuulie, you nut. Come on. I want to talk to Dana.
祖伊，你這瘋子， 我想跟丹娜談談
Relax. Dana. Can I talk to Dana?
冷靜，我可以跟丹娜談談嗎？
- There is no Dana, only Zuul. - You must have some singing voice.
-沒有丹娜，只有祖伊 -你定有一副好嗓子
I'll count to three. If I can't talk to Dana, there'll be trouble.
我數到三，如果我 不能跟她談，你將有麻煩
One ...
一…
Two ...
二…
Two and a half ...
兩聲半…
Please come down.
請下來
I am the Kéymaster. The Destructor will come.
我是主人，破壞者快來了
Gatekeeper.
是守門員
I am Vinz Clortho, Kéymaster of Gozer. Are you the Gatekeeper?.
我是戈薩的主人，你是守門員？
Hey, do you want a ride?
要載你一程嗎？
Wait for the sign. Our prisoners will be released.
等候標志，我們的囚犯快獲釋
- You'll perish in flames! - What an asshole.
-你會魂飛魄散的 -神經病
- Dropping off or picking up? - Dropping off.
-交付還是運送？ -交付
We picked up this guy. I'm afraid to lock him up.
我們找到了這人， 我不敢把他關起來
I know you guys are into this stuff, so I figured we'd check with you.
因你們是內行人，可一起檢查
- Are you the Gatekeeper?. - You'd better bring him inside.
-你是守門員嗎？ -把他帶進去
- How kind. You're a humanitarian. - I don't think he's human.
-你真有人性 -他恐怕不是人
- What's your name? - Vinz Clortho, Kéymaster of Gozer.
-你叫什么名字？ -文斯克洛奧，戈薩的主人
His name is Louis Tully. He lives on Central Park West.
他叫路易斯，住在西中央公園
- Do you want coffee, Mr. Tully?. - Do I ..?
-要咖啡嗎？ -我可否…
- Yes, have some.
-可以
Vinz, what sign are you waiting for?.
文斯，你在等什么標志？
Gozer the Traveller will come in a pre-chosen form.
旅行者戈薩預先選好出現形式
During the rectification of the Vuldronaii, he came as a Torb.
他以托伯身分糾正沃塞尼
During the reconciliation of the Meketrex, he came as a giant Sloar!
又以巨人斯洛調停梅德斯
Many Shubs and Zuuls were roasted in the Sloar that day!
不少舒布人和祖伊人被烤
- Egon. - Excuse me.
-埃貢 -失陪了
There's something strange about that man.
這人有些古怪
I have a terrible feeling that something awful will happen to you.
我有不祥預兆，你會有麻煩
I'm afraid you're gonna die.
恐怕你會沒命
I'll get it.
我去接聽
- Hello? - Egon, It's Peter.
-你好嗎？ -埃貢，是彼得
I have news from Gozer.
我有戈薩的消息
I'm with Dana Barrett.
我跟丹娜巴雷特一起
The Goze has been putting some moves on my would-be girlfriend.
戈薩在對付我的未來女朋友
I think we can get her on "Wild Kingdom".
我們可帶她去“野王國”
I gave her 300 cc's of Thorazine. She's gonna take a nap now.
我幫她注射了藥物，她正睡覺
She says she's the Gatekeeper. Does that make sense to you?
她說自己是守門員，合理嗎？
- The Kéymaster is here with me. - We have to get them together.
-而主人跟我在一起 -得安排他們一起
- That would be very dangerous. - Hold on to him. I'm on my way.
-這是很危險的 -拖延他，我正趕來
Good.
好
Thank you, Vinz. I need Ray here immediately.
謝謝，文斯，我要雷伊馬上來
I have to go to work. Stay here in bed until I get back.
我要工作， 你留在床上直到我回來
- Ray, do you believe in God? - Never met him.
-雷伊，你相信神嗎？ -從沒見過它
I do. I love Jesus' style.
我見過，我愛基督
- The roofcap is made of magnesium. - What are you so involved with?
-屋頂由鎂建成 -你在搞什么？
These blueprints for Dana Barrett's apartment building are very strange.
丹娜的房子藍圖很怪異
Do you remember in the Bible about when the dead would rise?
圣經說死者何時升天？
I remember Revelations 7:12.
我記得是啟示錄七章十二節
"l looked as he opened the 6th seal. The sun became black as sackcloth."
揭開第六印后 太陽變得像黑毛巾一樣
- "The moon became as blood." - "The seas boiled. The skies fell."
-滿月紅得像血 -天塌海怒
- Judgement day.
-是審判日 -審判日
Every religion has its myth about the end of the world.
每個宗教對末日都有其看法
Maybe we've been so busy lately because the dead have been rising.
我們最近挺忙，因死者正出棺
How about a little music?
不如聽些音樂吧
This way.
這邊
Excuse me!
抱歉
- Where do think you're going? - Step aside or you'll be arrested.
-你們去哪里？ -讓開，否則逮捕你
You can't come in here without a warrant or something.
你沒有法院指示不能進來
Cease all commerce order, seizure of premises and an inspection order.
中止經營，充公產業和檢查令
- I'd like to do one more test. - Egon, he says they have a warrant.
-我想再做多一次試驗 -埃貢，他說有指示
- This is private property. - Shut these all off.
-這是私人物業 -關掉所有東西
That would be hazardous.
我警告你，這樣會造成禍害
You're facing federal prosecution. Shut off the beams, or we'll do it.
你正面對控訴，關掉光束 否則我們來關
Turning the high-voltage containment system off would cause an explosion.
關掉高伏特的系統會導致爆炸
Don't patronise me! I'm not stupid!
別保護我，我不是笨蛋
At ease, Officer. I want to co-operate in any way I can.
放心，我會跟你合作
You had your chance, but you insulted me. Now it's my turn.
你有機會，但你侮辱了我 現在該我了
- He wants to shut down the grid. - We won't be held responsible.
-他想關掉系統 -后果自負
- Shut it off! - Don't do it! I'm warning you.
-關掉它 -我警告你別這樣做
I've never seen anything like this before.
我從未見過這東西
Just shut it off.
只是關掉它
- Don't be a jerk. - If he does that again, shoot him.
-別做蠢事 -他再這樣就開槍
- Don't tell me how to do myjob. - Shut it off!
-別教我怎樣做 -關掉它
Oh, shit.
糟了
Clear the building!
快離開這里
- This is the sign! - Yeah. We're going out of business.
-這是標志 -對，我們要結束營業了
- What happened? - The storage facility blew.
-什么事？ -儲存庫發生爆炸
- That's bad, isn't it? - Where's the Kéymaster?.
-糟了？ -主人在哪里？
- Shit! - Who's the Kéymaster?.
-該死 -主人是誰？
Arrest these men! They are violating the Environmental Protection Act.
拘捕他們，他們違反環保法案
- This explosion is a result of it! - Your mother ..!
-結果引起爆炸 -你這畜生…
Columbia Building, 57th Street. I'm in a hurry.
快去五十七街哥倫比亞大廈
Guard! I want to make a phone call!
守衛，我想打個電話
I wasn't even there!
我甚至不在現場
The roofcap structure is like what NASA uses to identify dead pulsars.
屋頂結構物像用來分辨星球
Cold-riveted girders with cores of pure selenium.
鉚釘主梁附有硒光電線
Does everybody get it?
大家都明白嗎？
- They're not made that way anymore? - Nobody ever made them like this!
-不會再有這種建筑吧？ -沒人這樣做了
The architect was either a genius or a wacko!
建筑師不是天才就是瘋子
Ray, for a moment, pretend I don't know anything -
雷伊，現在假裝 我對冶金術和物理
- about metallurgy or physics.
一竅不通
- Just tell me what's going on. - You never studied.
-然后告訴我發生什么事 -你從未學過
The whole building is a super-conductive antenna -
整座大樓是一個超導的天線
- that was designed expressly for pulling in spiritual turbulence.
容易招惹魔鬼
Your girlfriend lives in the corner penthouse of Spook Central.
你的女友住在閣樓角落
She's not my girlfriend. She's interesting as a client -
她不是我女友，是有趣的客人
- because she sleeps four feet above her covers.
因為她睡在床鋪上空四英尺處
- She barks, drools, claws. - It's the building.
-她吠叫、流口水和抓東西 -全是大樓在作怪
This building is the door to something terrible.
這里會通往可怕的地方
The architect was lvo Shandor.
建筑師是伊沃尚德
He was a doctor who performed a lot of unnecessary surgery.
他是個做過很多 沒必要手術的醫生
- He started a secret society. - Let me guess. Gozer worshippers.
-還成立秘密社團 -讓我猜猜，戈薩的門徒
- Right. - "No studying" ...
-對 -誰說我沒學過
After WW l, Shandor decided society was too sick to survive.
第一次世界大戰后 尚德認為社團無法生存
He had nearly a thousand followers. They conducted rituals on the roof.
他有近一千名信徒， 他們曾在樓頂舉行過儀式
They intended to bring about the end of the world. Now it may happen.
他們想世界末日到來， 現在也許會成真
So be good, forgoodness'sake! somebody's coming
那別犯罪，因有人來了
- We have to find a judge. - Hey! Hold it!
-我們要去找法官 -等等
Are we gonna tell a federal judge -
我們是否要告訴聯邦法官
- that some mouldy Babylonian god is gonna tear up the city?.
有些巴比倫神想摧毀城市嗎？
- Sumerian, not Babylonian. - I've got to get my own lawyer.
-是蘇美爾人，不是巴比倫人 -我要找我自己的律師
Ghostbusters, the mayor wants you. The whole island's going crazy.
魔鬼克星，市長想見你， 這城市快瘋了
I've got to split, the mayor wants me.
我要走了，市長想見我
- I am the Kéymaster. - I am the Gatekeeper.
-我是主人 -我是守門員
Stay back!
退后
- You're not giving me any answers! - We're blocking bridges, roads ...
-你還沒回答我 -我們堵塞了橋梁和道路
- The Ghostbusters are here. - Okay, the Ghostbusters.
-魔鬼克星在這里 -好的，魔鬼克星
- Where's this Peck?. - I'm Peck. I want to make a report.
-帕克在哪里？ -我就是，我想向你報告
These men use nerve gasses to induce hallucinations.
他們用神經毒氣去制造幻象
People think they're seeing ghosts and they call these bozos, -
他們指人家見到的魔鬼是笨蛋
- who show up with a fake light show.
而它們發出的光是假的
- Dickless here shut off our grid. - They caused an explosion!
-是這混蛋關掉系統的 -是他們造成爆炸
- Is this true? - Yes. This man has no dick.
-是真的嗎？ -對，這人沒那家伙
- All right. - That's what I heard.
-好吧 -這是我聽到的
- What is this? - It was no light show this morning.
-這是什么？ -今早沒有閃光表演
I've seen every form of combustion, but this beats the hell out of me.
所有殲滅法中以這個最為厲害
The walls in the 53rd Precinct were bleeding.
第五十三區的椈擎砲X血來
- Good afternoon. - Your Eminence.
-午安 -紅衣主教
- How are you? - You're looking good.
-你好嗎？ -你精神不錯
We're in a real fix. What should I do?
我們大禍臨頭了，我該怎做？
The church won't take any position on the religious implications.
教會對宗教含意不會表態
Personally, I think it's a sign from God.
就我個人而言， 我認為是神的指示
- But don't quote me on that. - That's a smart move.
-但別引述我的話 -真機靈
I won't call a press conference and tell everyone to start praying.
我不會開記者會叫人祈禱的
I've only been with the company two weeks, but I have to tell you, -
我跟同伴一起兩星期， 但我只能告訴你…
- these things are real. I have seen shit that'll turn you white.
這些事千真萬確，會嚇死你的
You can believe Mr. Pecker, -
你可以相信帕克先生
- or accept the onset of a disaster of Biblical proportion.
或圣經預言慘劇快開始了
- What do you mean? - Old Testament, wrath-of-God stuff.
-什么意思？ -舊約說神很憤怒
- Fire and brimstone coming down. - Earthquakes, volcanoes ...
-有火和硫磺正下來 -地震和火山爆發
- The dead rising from the grave! - Human sacrifice, mass hysteria!
-死人復活 -人類犧牲，歇斯底里發作
Enough, I get the point! But what if you're wrong?
夠了，我明白了， 但如果你錯了呢？
Nothing happens! We go to jail, quietly. We'll enjoy it.
只當沒有任何事發生， 我們靜靜地進牢，好好活著
But if I'm right, and we can stop this thing ...
但若沒說錯，我們能制止這事
... you will have saved the lives of millions of registered voters.
你將拯救千千萬萬的選民
I don't believe you're seriously considering listening to these men.
我不相信你會慎重地考慮 他們的話
- Get him out of here. - Bye.
-帶他離開 -再見
- I'll fix you, Venkman. - I'm gonna miss him!
-文卡曼，我會報仇 -我會掛念他
What do you need from me?
你想我怎樣做？
Let's run some red lights!
開警燈快走吧！
Hello, New York!
紐約好
Dr. Ray Stanz. The heart of the Ghostbusters!
雷伊斯坦是魔鬼克星的核心
They love you ... I like that shirt, friend.
他們愛你… 我喜歡這上衣，朋友
Got to run. Got a date with a ghost. Whatever happens, be professional.
跟魔鬼約會，得以專業行事
This might require overtime!
這樣可能要超時工作
There they are!
他們在那里
It's all right. We're fine!
好了，我們很好
We can handle it! They want to play rough.
既然他們想玩，我們奉陪到底
Ghostbusters! Ghostbusters!
魔鬼克星
Do you want to play rough? Let's do it!
你想玩嗎？工作吧
- Where are we? - In the teens, somewhere ...
-我們在哪里？ -十幾樓…
When we get to twenty, tell me. I'm gonna throw up.
到二十就告訴我，我會嘔吐的
- Twenty-two. Is this it? - Yeah.
-是二十二嗎？ -對
- Art Deco. Very nice. - It's at the end of the hall.
-藝術裝飾，真美 -在大堂盡頭
Where do these stairs go?
這些樓梯通往哪里？
They go up.
他們通往上面
Go ahead. Come on.
繼續前進，來吧
Dana!
丹娜
Okay, she's a dog.
她是一條狗
It's a girl.
是個女子
- It's Gozer. - I thought Gozer was a man.
-是戈薩 -我以為戈薩是男性
Whatever it is, it has to get by us.
總之它要通過我們這一關
Go get her, Ray!
雷伊，快去抓她
Gozer the Gozarian!
戈薩人
Good evening. As a representative of the city of New York, -
晚上好， 我以紐約市代表的身分
- I order you to cease all supernatural activity -
下令你停止所有超自然活動
- and return to your place of origin.
并返回原來的地方
- That ought to do it. Thanks, Ray. - Are you a god?
-必須這樣做，謝謝，雷伊 -你是神嗎？
- No. - Then ... die!
-不 -那去死吧
When someone asks you if you're a god, say "yes"!
如果有人這樣問你， 該回答“是”
All right, this chick is toast!
好，這姑娘要完蛋了！
- Grab your stick. - Holding!
-抓著棍子 -抓住了
- Heat them up! - Smoking!
-加熱 -冒煙
- Make them hard! - Ready!
-用力 -準備
Let's show this prehistoric bitch how we do things downtown.
讓我們表演這個史前婆娘 如何在市中心工作
Throw it!
射
- Nimble little minx. - Go full stream.
-小女孩挺敏捷的 -發射全部光線
Aim for the flat-top!
目的是平頂物
That wasn't so hard.
那并不困難
We neutronised it. A complete particle reversal.
我們把粒子變為中性
- We had the tools and the talent! - It's Miller time.
-我們有工具和才華 -是喝酒時間
Ray, this looks extraordinarily bad.
雷伊，看來很不妙
Look out!
小心
Sub-creatures! Gozer the Gozerian, the Destructor, Zildrohar...
次等生物！戈薩、破壞者…
The Travellerhas come. Choose andperish.
旅行者已到，選擇后消失
What do you mean?
什么意思？
Choose. Choose the form ofthe Destructor.
選擇，選擇破壞者的形式
I get it! Very cute.
我明白了，很可愛呢
Whatever we think of will appear and destroy us. Empty your heads!
無論想什么都會毀滅我們， 別想了吧
- Don't think of anything. - The choice is made.
-那什么也別想 -也就是選了
- The Travellerhas come. - Nobody chose anything!
-旅行者已到 -沒有人選擇
Did you choose anything? Did you? I didn't choose anything!
你選了沒有？我什么也沒選
I couldn't help it. It just popped in there.
我無法自拔，它跳到里面了
- What just popped in there? - I tried to think.
-什么跳進去了？ -我正在想
- Look! - No! It can't be.
-看 -不，不會的
- What did you do? - Oh, shit!
-你做什么？ -該死
It's the Stay-Puft Marshmallow Man.
是棉花糖人
- You don't see thatevery day. - It was something I loved as a kid.
-不是每天都能看到的 -所以我想到卡通人物
Something that could never destroy us. Mr. Stay-Puft.
沒有東西能毀滅我們 棉花糖先生
Nice thinking.
想得好
We used to roast Stay-Puft marshmallows by the fire.
我們以前用火來烤棉花糖
Ray has gone bye-bye. What have you got left?
雷伊腦子壞了，我們還有什么？
I'm terrified beyond the capacity for rational thought.
我害怕得失去理性
- Oh, no. - Mother puss bucket!
-不 -該死
- Nobody steps on a church here! - One, two, three, roast him!
-別踐踏教堂 -一、二、三，烤他
It's funny, us getting killed by a 100-foot marshmallow man.
有趣，百英尺棉花糖人追殺我們
Stay-Puft is okay. He's a sailor in New York. We'll get him laid.
棉花糖人沒事，他是紐約海員 給他個妞就好了
We could reverse the particle flow through the gate.
我們可更改粒子的流動方向
- How?. - We'll cross the streams.
-怎樣？ -令光線相交
- You said that was bad. - Cross the streams ...
-你說過這樣就糟了 -光線相交…
You're endangering the nice lady who paid us before she became a dog.
你在危害在變成狗之前 付錢給我們的女士
There's a slim chance we'll survive.
但我們的生存機會不大
- I love this plan! Let's do it! - This job isn't worth the money.
-我愛這計劃，行動 -這工作不值得
Hurry!
快些
See you on the other side.
在另一邊見
Nice working with you.
很高興跟你合作
Turn them on, Spengler!
斯彭勒，打開它們
- Are you all right? - Yeah.
-你們沒事吧？ -沒事
Venkman ... Spengler! Venkman!
文卡曼…斯彭勒！ 文卡曼！
Spengler! Spengler, are you okay?.
斯彭勒！斯彭勒，你沒事吧？
- I feel like the floor of a taxi. - Venky!
-我感到像計程車地板 -文卡曼
Thank God.
謝天謝地
- Are you okay?. - I'm all right.
-你沒事吧？ -我很好
- Fine.
-沒事
It smells like barbecued dog hair.
是燒狗毛的味道
Oh, Venkman, I'm sorry.
文卡曼，對不起
I'm sorry. I just forgot.
抱歉，我一時忘記了
Look!
看
Turn on the lights!
快來開燈
Go check on that little guy.
快去照顧那小子
What happened?
發生了什么事？
Where am l?
我在哪里？
Oh, hi.
你好
The superintendent will be pissed.
警官會大發雷霆的
- Are you okay?. - Who are you guys?
-你沒事吧？ -你們是誰？
We're the Ghostbusters.
我們是魔鬼克星
- Who does your taxes? - You are a fortunate individual.
-誰幫你做務稅？ -你走運了
You have participated in the biggest inter-dimensional rip since 1909.
你走進1909年來最大的空間
We'd like a sample of your brain.
我們想要你腦袋的樣本
I love this town!
我愛這個城市
What's going on? Does anyone want an interview?. I'm an eyewitness!
怎么樣了？想跟我談談嗎？ 我是目擊證人